# KATERYNA LANINA

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER











https://github.com/lanina90



https://t.me/KaterynaLanina



in linkedin.com/in/kateryna-lanina/

## PROFILE

Motivated Front-End Developer with a strong foundation in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. My technical skills focus on JavaScript, TypeScript, React, NextJs, and Redux. I am able to create new functionality and support and extend existing ones. I work without supervision. I began my career in SEO and worked my way up to Head of the SEO department over the span of ten years. I believe my previous experience and front-end skills can be quite useful for your projects. I could say that I am a responsible and self-motivated person and a good team player.

## SKILLS

#### JavaScript

- **Typescript**
- HTML5/CSS/SCSS
- CSS Modules
- React / NextJs
- Tailwind
- Git
- Figma, Abstract

# LANGUAGES

Ukrainian - Native English - B1

# **EDUCATION**

**Economic and Management** Lviv National Politechnic University

2007-2013

# EXPERIENCE

#### JUNIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Miteyda

02/2024 - now

Responsibilities:

- Translating complex design requirements into interactive user experiences
- Developing new system functionality and introduction of changes to existing functionality
- Refactoring and bug fixing of existing functionality
- Writing reusable and maintainable components
- Using Git to manage codebase

Techology Stack: React, TypesScript, NextJS, SCSS, MUI

#### JUNIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

BazaTrainee Ukraine

07/2023 - 02/2024

Responsibilities:

- Developed an interactive layout, using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to generate an improved user experience and ensure high-quality design and crossbrowser compatibility
- Regularly debugged code and maintained quality standards.
- Coordinated a teams of 2-3 frontend developers
- Working on 2-3 projects in parallel

Relized 5 MVP projects using React, TypesScript, NextJS, Tailwind, SCSS, Jest. Each team consisted of 2-4 designers, 2-5 QAs, 2-5 front-end developers, 1-2 backend developers.

#### **PORTFOLIO**

# Chytozavryk

Team size: 8

The main purpose of the project is to make reading more engaging for children. The platform includes dashboards for parents and children, quizzes pages and admin panel. My responsibilities included finalizing the development of the child's dashboard, and developing the admin panel from scratch. Additionally, I coordinated a team of 3 frontend developers

Technologies: NextJs, SCSS, TypeScript, React-query, Formik

**StatusAC** 

Team size: 5

Website for law company. I joined the project during its final stages. My primary responsibilities included optimizing the website for mobile devices and implementing modifications requested by the client. The most significant challenge I faced was working with styled components, a technology with which I had no prior experience. This required a rapid learning curve and adaptability to integrate effectively with the existing codebase.

Technologies: React, styled components

**Cat For Future** 

Team size: 6

The primary goal of the project is to find new homes for kittens. It incorporates functionalities such as the reservation and cancellation of cat adoptions, user registration, and authentication. My role in the project was to develop an administrative panel, implement authentication and registration processes. Also, I coordinated a team of 2 frontend developers

Technologies: React, SCSS, TypeScript, RTK Query, Formik

Al Email

Website GIT

**Team size:** PET-project

This is a personal project, with the primary objective being the enhancement of my proficiency in Next.js, alongside an improvement of my SCSS and animation skills.

Technologies: NextJs, SCSS, TypeScript

# **Digital Production Studio**

Team size: PET-project

This is a personal project, with the primary objective being the enhancement of my proficiency in Next.js, alongside an improvement of my SCSS and animation skills.

Technologies: NextJs, SCSS, TypeScript

<u>See my portfolio</u>